Forbidden to remember. Terrified to forget.
The Twilight Saga: New Moon is a adventure, fantasy,
drama film directed by Chris Weitz.
Forks, Washington resident Bella Swan is reeling from the departure of her vampire love,
Edward Cullen, and finds comfort in her friendship with Jacob Black, a werewolf.
But before she knows it, she's thrust into a centuries-old conflict, and her desire to
be with Edward at any cost leads her to take greater and greater risks.
Bella Swan, played by Kristen Stewart.
Edward Cullen, played by Robert Pattinson.
Jacob Black, played by Taylor Lautner.
Jane, played by Dakota Fanning.
Aro, played by Michael Sheen.
Alice Cullen, played by Ashley Greene.
The Twilight Saga: New Moon is a 2009 American vampire romantic fantasy film directed by Chris Weitz from
a screenplay by Melissa Rosenberg, based on the 2006 novel New Moon by Stephenie Meyer.
It is the sequel to Twilight (2008) and the second
installment in The Twilight Saga film series.
The film stars Kristen Stewart, Robert Pattinson, and Taylor Lautner, reprising their
roles as Bella Swan, Edward Cullen, and Jacob Black, respectively.
In the film, Bella gets closer with Jacob, who is a werewolf, after Edward leaves her, but when the
vampire decides to take a drastic move, she must make a decision between the two.
Summit Entertainment announced it had greenlit the film on November
22, 2008, following the early success of Twilight.
Principal photography began on March 23, 2009, in Vancouver,
Canada, and ended in Montepulciano, Italy on May 29.
The Twilight Saga: New Moon premiered at the Mann Village Theater in Westwood, California on November 16,
2009, and was theatrically released in the United States on November 20, by Summit Entertainment.
The film received generally negative reviews from critics, but grossed $711
million worldwide, becoming the seventh-highest-grossing film of 2009.
It set domestic box office records as the biggest midnight opening in the United States and Canada,
grossing $26.3 million, which was superseded by its sequel, The Twilight Saga: Eclipse.
This led to the highest single-day domestic gross on an opening day, with $72.7 million,
until it was beaten by Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows – Part 2 (2011).
The film also became the widest independent release, playing in 4,024
theaters, until it was surpassed by The Twilight Saga: Eclipse.
New Moon was released on DVD and Blu-ray on March 20, 2010.
As of July 2012, the film has grossed $184.9 million in North American DVD sales, selling more than 8.8 million units, four
million of which were sold within its first weekend, beating Twilight's 3.8 million units sold in its first two days.
The film was followed by three more sequels, The Twilight Saga: Eclipse, The Twilight Saga: Breaking Dawn –
Part 1, and The Twilight Saga: Breaking Dawn – Part 2, in 2010, 2011, and 2012, respectively.
The film explores themes of moon, based on novel or
book, vampire, teen movie, werewolf.
The tone is emotional.